New York State Office of Educational Television and Public Broadcasting; Records apap376
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Office of Educational Television and Public Broadcasting Records, Office of Cultural Education, New York State Education Department
1989-1998
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
University of the State of New York. -- Office of Educational Television and Public Broadcasting
apap376
1.31 cubic ft.
This collection consists of video and audio acquired by the Office of Educational Television and Public Broadcasting, Office of Cultural Education, New York State Education Department containing various programs that were created by or in collaboration with public broadcasting stations around the state.
Content Description
This collection consists of video and audio acquired by the Office of Educational Television and Public Broadcasting, Office of Cultural Education, New York State Education Department containing various programs that were created by or in collaboration with public broadcasting stations around the state. The video is stored on VHS tapes, Betacams, and 3/4 Umatics. There are a small number of CDs as well as supplemental study guides. The material is predominantly appropriate for a K-8 audience.
Administrative History
The Office of Educational Television and Public Broadcasting is a program of the Office of Cultural Education in the New York State Education Department. Its public television and radio stations are chartered by the Board of Regents and are therefore institutions within the University of the State of New York. Each station is an independent media outlet.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is unprocessed and is likely disorganized. Individual items may be difficult to find.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The New York State Archives donated all materials in this collection to the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives in June 2018.
Access
Access to this collection is unrestricted.
Education; Radio and Television Broadcasting; Educational broadcasting--New York (State); VHS (TM)
- Angelo Del Toro Puerto Rican/Hispanic Youth Leadership Institute, Undated (Vhs 1)
- Cultural Education and a New Compact for Learning, Undated (Vhs 2)
- Cultural Education in New York State, Undated (Vhs 3)
- The Emergency Exercise: Testing Your School's Disaster Plan, Undated (Beta 1)
- Go for it! A Career Video for Early Teens - English, Undated (Vhs 4)
- Go for it! A Career Video for Early Teens - Spanish, Undated (Vhs 5)
- Goodbye to Yesterday: A Profile of School Change in Math, Science & Technology, Undated (Vhs 6)
- Jazz Makers #2, Undated (Vhs 7)
- Just Think Problem Solving Through Inquiry, 1996 (Vhs 8)
- Just Think Problem Solving Through Inquiry, 1998 (Cd 1)
- Just Think Problem Solving Through Inquiry: Assessment, 1996 (Vhs 9)
- Just Think Problem Solving Through Inquiry: Design, 1996 (Vhs 10)
- Just Think Problem Solving Through Inquiry: Discourse, 1996 (Vhs 11)
- Just Think Problem Soling Through Inquiry: Guidebook, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Just Think Problem Solving Through Inquiry: Inquiry, 1996 (Vhs 12)
- Just Think Problem Solving Through Inquiry: Partnerships, 1996 (Vhs 13)
- Just Think Problem Solving Through Inquiry: Research, 1996 (Vhs 14)
- Just Think Problem Solving Through Inquiry: Starts, 1996 (Vhs 15)
- Konecnik [Ed] - Music Videos, Undated (Vhs 16)
- Kosmo Brushton Moira School, Undated (Vhs 17)
- Learning Link, Undated (Beta 2)
- Mental Model Building, Group #2, Undated (Vhs 18)
- Minds on Math & Science, Undated (Vhs 19)
- National Gardening Association - Grow Lab: A Growing Experience, 1991 (Vhs 20)
- NCREST - Using Standards and Assessments to Support Teaching and Learning: Early Lessons from New York State, 1997 (Vhs 21)
- New York Learns: Standards in Our Schools: Administrators & Staff, 1997 (Umatic 1)
- New York Learns: Standards in Our Schools: Elementary Standards, 1996 (Umatic 2)
- New York Network - CPB President's Message on Ready to Learn, 1993 (Vhs 22)
- New York State Education Department Level II Science Videos Companion Workbooks in English and Spanish, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- New York State Education Department Level II Science Videos Teacher' Guide, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Nurses Teleconference, 1989 (Vhs 23)
- On the Road to Reform: School Change that Works, Undated (Vhs 24)
- Parents as Partners: New Directions in Education, WNED Buffalo, 1993 (Vhs 25)
- Principles of Engineering: A High School Course in Problem Solving, A Video Introduction, Undated (Vhs 26)
- Reaching Higher Standards in New York, 1997 (Vhs 27)
- Round Table Discussion A-Roll Reel 1 of 2 w/ Time Code Burned In, Undated (Vhs 28)
- Say Yes to Success! A Profile of School Change in Math, Science & Technology, Undated (Vhs 29)
- Schoenherr [Ronald L.] - Greenville SDE Pres., SCED Importance of Technology Communications, 1991 (Vhs 30)
- School to Work: Getting Down to Business, Undated (Vhs 31)
- Science: Bulbs, Batteries & Wires, English Version, Undated (Vhs 32)
- Science: Bulbs, Batteries & Wires, Spanish Version, Undated (Vhs 33)
- Science: Buoyancy, Spanish Version, Undated (Vhs 34)
- Science: Butterflies, English Version, Undated (Vhs 35)
- Science: Butterflies, Spanish Version, Undated (Vhs 36)
- Science: Plant Life Cycle, English Version, Undated (Vhs 37)
- Science: Plant Life Cycle, Spanish Version, Undated (Vhs 38)
- Science Kit Demonstrations, Anchorage School District, Undated (Vhs 39)
- Snapshots of a Changing School, Undated (Vhs 40)
- SUNY Oneonta/CSEA Local 635, 1990 Special Achievement Award (Vhs 41)
- Tapping Potential: Practicing Equity in the Classroom, Undated (Vhs 42)
- Unicef - 1994 Day of the African Child (Beta 3)
- Unicef - 1994 Day of the African Child (Vhs 43)
- Video Production Workshop, Undated (Vhs 44)
- Visions & Dreams: A Tribute to HEOP, Undated (Vhs 45)
- Whose School Is It?, Undated (Vhs 46)